# JAKE MCCAMBLEY SOFTWARE ENGINEER

jakemccambley.com // jake.mccambley@gmail.com linkedin.com/jakemccambley // github.com/McCambley (203) 644 3093 // open to relocation

### **PROFILE**

Full stack JavaScript developer with a background in mental health counseling, conservation, and management within the nonprofit sector. I've worked across industries to bring people together in order to excel as a team. Now, having discovered a passion for connection and collaboration in the software space, I lead teams that ship clean code to production.

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Apiary**

#### Full Stack Developer - Winter 2020 - Present

Produced full scale applications for early stage startups geared towards optimizing performance, SEO, maintainability, and accessibility.

- DotCot: An application to connect investors and startups
- Apiary: A landing page for Practicum by Yandex's Startup Accelerator Program
- Prim-U: A landing page for a South African beauty company

# **Appalachian Mountain Club Huts Field Coordinator -** Spring 2019 - Winter 2020

The Appalachian Mountain Club is a nonprofit conservation organization whose mission is to provide educational opportunities to the public through outdoor recreation.

- Developed and led staff trainings for eighty new employees twice a year
- Performed weekly feedback driven site to ensure consistent mission oriented outcomes.

# **Spring Lake Ranch** *House Advisor and Crew Leader - Winter*2019 - Spring 2020

Spring Lake Ranch is a therapeutic community in the Green Mountains of Vermont.

 Guided at risk adults in operating a ranch and building community in a therapeutic setting.

# **EDUCATION**

#### Practicum by Yandex October 2021

Full-Stack Web Development

Wake Forest University, May 2015

Psychology | Entrepreneurship & Social Enterprise

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **DotCot - Live**

React // Node.is // Express // MongoDB // AWS

Lets investors create custom forms to allow startups to apply for venture capital funding

- Lead a core feature team of three with an agile workflow using Trello, Git flow, and regular stand-ups
- Implemented authentication flow using Passport with Google, Facebook, and LinkedIn Strategies
- Built a scalable backend for the application's REST Api using Express.js and MongoDB complete with session persistence, error handling, and unit-testing with Mocha
- Configured scripts for efficient Continuous Integration to ensure a seamless development experience

#### **NewsExplorer - Live | Repository**

React // Node.js // Express // MongoDB // Styled-Components

An application that allows users to search for and save the most relevant news of the day

- Created a performant SPA with React and Styled-Components that utilizes the NewsAPI
- Deployed a server built with Express.js and MongoDB using a Linux VM on Google Cloud
- Built a RESTful API with full CRUD capabilities protected by JWT Authentication and data encryption

#### **Around the U.S. - Live | Repository**

React // Node.js // Express // MongoDB // Google Cloud

A photo sharing social network

- Created an SPA with React on the frontend and Express.js and MongoDB on the backend
- Constructed a RESTful API with full CRUD capabilities protected by JWT Authentication and data encryption
- Served with nginx on Google Cloud using a Linux Virtual Machine

#### **Apiary - Live | Repository**

React // GraphQL // Apollo // Contentful

A landing page for Practicum by Yandex's Apiary program

- Lead a four person team in building a React SPA in an effective agile and asynchronous environment with git flow
- Configured connection between application and Contentful using GraphQL with Apollo for seamless and real-time content management

## **SKILLS**

JavaScript | React | MongoDB | Express | Node.js | HTML5 | CSS3 | Git & GitHub | GraphQL | NoSql | npm | Unit Testing | OOP | Continuous Integration (CI) | UI/UX| Google Cloud | REST APIs | Agile | Algorithms